All mammals take in oxygen from the air they breathe in, and release CO₂ from their blood when breathing out.
所有哺乳动物都从吸入的空气中获取氧气，在呼气时把血液中的二氧化碳排出。
Most mammals can’t directly detect oxygen levels in the blood supplied to their tissues.
大多数哺乳动物无法直接察觉输送到身体组织的血液中的氧含量。
Instead, they rely on the rising level of CO₂ in their blood to signal that they might need to take a breath.
相反，它们依靠血液中不断升高的二氧化碳水平发出的信号，得知自己可能需要呼吸了。
But a recent study published in Science suggests seals can sense the amount of oxygen in the blood, and change their diving behavior in response.
但发表在《科学》杂志上的一项最新研究表明，海豹能感知血液中的氧气含量，并据此改变潜水行为。
To find out if oxygen levels affected seal behavior, Professor McKnight at the University of St. Andrews and his colleagues created a special section in a pool where young seals were held.
为了弄清氧气水平是否会影响海豹的行为，圣安德鲁斯大学的麦克奈特教授和同事在饲养幼年海豹的水池中专门隔出了一块区域。
In one corner, there was a breathing chamber, where they were sheltered from the rain and the wind.
在一个角落里有一个呼吸室，海豹在那里可以躲避风雨。
The breathing chamber was surrounded by panels that prevented surface swimming, yet swimming below the surface for about 200 feet would give the seals access to a feeder where they could eat as much fish as they liked.
呼吸室四周围着挡板，使海豹无法在水面游动；但如果在水下潜游大约200英尺，海豹就能到达一个投食点，在那里想吃多少鱼就吃多少。
Once the seals got familiar with the setup, the researchers started to gradually change the composition of the air in the breathing chamber, increasing or reducing the levels of oxygen and CO₂ to see an effect on their behavior.
海豹熟悉了这一实验布置后，研究人员开始逐渐改变呼吸室内的空气成分，提高或降低氧气和二氧化碳的含量，看看这对它们的行为有什么影响。
Sure enough, the higher the level of oxygen, the longer the seals stayed at the feeder.
果然，氧气含量越高，海豹在投食点停留的时间就越长。
The finding suggests that seals don’t just physically respond to oxygen levels by changing their heart rate or breathing, but that they are sufficiently aware of them to change their behavior.
这一发现表明，海豹不只是在生理上通过改变心率或呼吸来对氧气水平做出反应，而且能足够清楚地察觉到氧气水平，从而改变自己的行为。
This ability would put seals in a class beyond any land mammals that have been tested.
这种能力会让海豹超越所有接受过测试的陆地哺乳动物。
Since oxygen levels on land remain stable, humans don’t seem to have evolved to notice low blood oxygen levels, sometimes not even when they’re about to pass out in free-diving.
由于陆地上的氧气水平保持稳定，人类似乎并没有进化出察觉血氧过低的能力，有时甚至在自由潜水中即将昏厥时也察觉不到。
Therefore, in free-diving without oxygen tanks, accidents are quite common.
因此，在不带氧气瓶的自由潜水中，事故相当常见。
Our reliance on sensing CO₂ levels in our blood instead of oxygen may be to blame.
我们依靠感知血液中的二氧化碳水平而不是氧气水平，这或许就是原因所在。
Actually, this is a perfectly reasonable strategy on land, where growing CO₂ tends to signal breathing issues.
其实，在陆地上这是一种完全合理的策略，因为在陆地上二氧化碳升高往往意味着呼吸出了问题。
But when we hold our breath during diving, relying on CO₂ levels is risky, especially on repeated dives.
但当我们潜水屏住呼吸时，依靠二氧化碳水平是有风险的，尤其是在反复潜水时。
This is because every time we surface and breathe in, our sensitivity to CO₂ is decreased, even if its levels are already high, and this increases the chance that a person will, without awareness, pass out before they get to the surface.
这是因为每次我们浮出水面吸气时，我们对二氧化碳的敏感度就会降低，即使它的含量已经很高；这就增加了一个人在毫无察觉的情况下，在到达水面之前昏厥的可能性。